<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quentin Goehrig</title>
    <description>A website and blog for my .</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 20:11:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 20:11:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mirror Mirror! - How I Build a Magic Mirror</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mirror Mirror, who is the most elegant programmer of them all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/Cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dude, of course! One year ago I decided to join the Internet of Things community enthusiasts and went out to built my very own smart mirror. For those unaware, a smart mirror is a double-sided mirror that sits in front of a monitor attached to a computer, raspberry pi being the popular choice. This post won’t dive into the technical aspects of the hardware or software, but rather to give an overview of the approach and hopefully provide some tips for future builders. If you’re looking for a more detailed guide on the hardware behind building a magic mirror, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.dylanjpierce.com/raspberrypi/magicmirror/tutorial/2015/12/27/build-a-magic-mirror.html&quot;&gt;Dylan Pierce’s&lt;/a&gt; blog post as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fkVBAcvbrjU&amp;amp;t=&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by HackerHouse. If you’re looking for a guide on the software behind these these mirrors, checkout out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichMich/MagicMirror&quot;&gt;MagicMirror²&lt;/a&gt; project. MagicMirror² is an open-source, modular smart-mirror platform that has some built-in widgets and and a growing library of third party modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-monitor&quot;&gt;The Monitor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning on building a smart mirror or another panel-based IOT device, the monitor should to be your starting point. Since the size of your monitor orders the size of your frame, you need to select a size before you go out and start buying materials. I recommend going bigger if you can. I got lucky and found a bright 25” monitor on craigslist that worked great. Any type should do, but you’ll probably want to find one that’s fairly bright that has HDMI input. Oh, and you have to be content with removing the bezel from your monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mirror&quot;&gt;The Mirror&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the type of mirror halted my progress for a while. Despite really only two main choices, glass and acrylic, it seemed like there were a lot of factors to consider. I This is what I determined for my build, and is subjective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Acrylic&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Glass&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;lighter&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;heavier&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;susceptible&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;fun house&quot; effect&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;none&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;more&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;light passage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;less&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;less&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;price&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;more&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;low&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chance of breaking&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;high&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nope&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;smudge resistance&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;nope&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I chose to go with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/12-Acrylic-See-Through-Mirror-1mm/dp/B01G4MQ966/ref=sr_1_1?s=home-garden&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1520304107&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=see%2Bthrough%2Bglass&amp;amp;th=1&quot;&gt;this 12” x 24”  3mm thick&lt;/a&gt; acrylic mirror. I can see why some builders choose glass over acrylic. The rigidness of the glass prevents bends and warps in the mirror. This is that “fun house” effect I mentioned above. However, the light passage on most of these mirrors, even the ones that are specifically targeted towards smart mirror builders still didn’t seem to have enough light passage to create a display that really pops. I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWSolSxpRT4&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; illustrates this well. There is a third option, mirror film, which is applied over a standard mirror. This seems to be a fairly popular choice for builders going for larger displays, like a big bathroom mirror. I didn’t investigate much into these, but you can find plenty of information about them in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://magicmirror.builders/&quot;&gt;MM builders forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-box&quot;&gt;The Box&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the casing and front-facing frame is likely the most taxing and time consuming part of the build process. It’s helpful to have someone with at least some basic carpentry skills at your side for this part. Thankfully I had my stepfather, Dave, to help me here. Many guides recommend using 2 x 4’s to build the casings. However, we went with a 1 x 3 approach which resulted in a really slim and sleek looking case. We used similar boards to build the frame for the front. I won’t go into the details here since the dimensions of your frame will be different than mine, but it’s best to not over-think and do whichever works best for the type of mirror you’d like to build. 0Stick to a rigid guide if need be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some select guides I’ve not mentioned that recommend using nails to secure the frame. An easier approach is to use glue, liquid nails or otherwise, to secure the boards together and then use screws for additional security. The screw sizes should depend on the thickness of your boards, just ask your local home depot dude! What I’ve gather from the MM community is that glue is a better and more reliable solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important detail to note: &lt;strong&gt;MAKE SURE YOUR MIRROR IS VENTILATED&lt;/strong&gt;. Seriously, this is a wood frame so make sure that you’re getting plenty of airflow to the mirror. I drilled several ~2.5” holes at the top and the bottom of my frame that gives the Pi and monitor enough breathing room to not burn your house down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IMGHERE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-software&quot;&gt;The Software&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend using MagicMirror² as starting point for the code that will power your mirror. MM² is equipped with powerful guides, a capable API, and plenty of community members who are willing to help you. Configuration is very easy and extensive. Also, since the project is open source you are free to tinker with the source yourself. I was able to get my mirror up and running while only having to write a few lines of code. Magic Mirror projects are built up of &lt;strong&gt;modules&lt;/strong&gt;. As the name suggests, modules control a contained component of the mirror. There are some default modules to get you going, such as a weather forecast widget, clock, news feed, and a few others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part about this platform is the large number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichMich/MagicMirror/wiki/3rd-party-modules&quot;&gt;third-party modules&lt;/a&gt; that are being developed and supported by the community. There are all sorts of modules ranging from IOT device management, voice control, media players, modules to manage other modules, and even one for facial recognition! There is also a template module for integrating your own projects into MM². I decided to include two additional modules into my mirror. One was to display my most recent emails, a pretty simple setup, and another to integrate some layer of voice control via Google Voice Assistant. Mostly, I use this to toggle the monitor display. The latter was a bit difficult and involved writing some custom scripts to turn the monitor on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my year with the completed mirror I have discovered a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checking and responding to email with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:07:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-08/magic-mirror</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-08/magic-mirror</guid>
        
        
        <category>iot</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World! - About This Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome! You’ve made it to my personal website/blog. I’ll be using this platform as a channel to highlight some of my skills as a software engineer and to hopefully introduce some insightful blog posts about technology and anything else I feel like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I likely won’t be posting all that often, as I’m still busy finishing up school at the University of Wisconsin-La Crosse and working as a software engineer at Trane. My intention is to make occasional, insightful blog posts for anything I might be interested in, so stay tuned and have great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-04/hello-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-04/hello-world</guid>
        
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
